[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "A SOP expression is equal to 1 ______________",
    "options": [
      "All the variables in domain of expression are present",
      "At least one variable in domain of expression is present.",
      "When one or more product terms in the expression are equal to 0.",
      "When one or more product terms in the expression are equal to 1."
    ],
    "correct": "When one or more product terms in the expression are equal to 1.",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The output $A < B$ is set to 1 when the input combinations is __________",
    "options": [
      "$A=10$, $B=01$",
      "$A=11$, $B=01$",
      "$A=01$, $B=01$",
      "$A=01$, $B=10$"
    ],
    "correct": "$A=01$, $B=10$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Two 2-bit comparator circuits can be connected to form single 4-bit comparator",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "High level Noise Margins ($V_{NH}$) of CMOS 5 volt series circuits is _________",
    "options": [
      "0.3 V",
      "0.5 V",
      "0.9 V",
      "3.3 V"
    ],
    "correct": "0.9 V",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "If we multiply “723” and “34” by representing them in floating point notation i.e. by first, converting them in floating point representation and then multiplying them, the value of mantissa of result will be ________",
    "options": [
      "24.582",
      "2.4582",
      "24582",
      "0.24582"
    ],
    "correct": "0.24582",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "The output of the expression $F=A+B+C$ will be Logic ________ when $A=0$, $B=1$, $C=1$. the symbol'+' here represents OR Gate.",
    "options": [
      "Undefined",
      "One",
      "Zero",
      "10 (binary)"
    ],
    "correct": "One",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "If an active-HIGH S-R latch has a 0 on the S input and a 1 on the R input and then the R input goes to 0, the latch will be ________.",
    "options": [
      "SET",
      "RESET",
      "Clear",
      "Invalid"
    ],
    "correct": "RESET",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "3.3 v CMOS series is characterized by __________ and _________ as compared to the 5 v CMOS series.",
    "options": [
      "Low switching speeds, high power dissipation",
      "Fast switching speeds, high power dissipation",
      "Fast switching speeds, very low power dissipation",
      "Low switching speeds, very low power dissipation"
    ],
    "correct": "Fast switching speeds, very low power dissipation",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The binary value “1010110” is equivalent to decimal __________",
    "options": [
      "86",
      "87",
      "88",
      "89"
    ],
    "correct": "86",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The _______ Encoder is used as a keypad encoder.",
    "options": [
      "2-to-8 encoder",
      "4-to-16 encoder",
      "BCD-to-Decimal",
      "Decimal-to-BCD Priority"
    ],
    "correct": "Decimal-to-BCD Priority",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "How many data select lines are required for selecting eight inputs?",
    "options": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct": "3",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "The diagram with NOT, AND, and OR gate levels shows the general implementation of ________ form",
    "options": [
      "Boolean",
      "Arbitrary",
      "POS",
      "SOP"
    ],
    "correct": "SOP",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The Quad Multiplexer has _____ outputs",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "4",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Demultiplexer has",
    "options": [
      "Single input and single outputs.",
      "Multiple inputs and multiple outputs.",
      "Single input and multiple outputs.",
      "Multiple inputs and single output."
    ],
    "correct": "Single input and multiple outputs.",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "The expression _________ is an example of Commutative Law for Multiplication.",
    "options": [
      "$AB+C = A+BC$",
      "$A(B+C) = B(A+C)$",
      "$AB=BA$",
      "$A+B=B+A$"
    ],
    "correct": "$AB=BA$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "\"Sum-of-Weights\" method is used __________",
    "options": [
      "to convert from one number system to other",
      "to encode data",
      "to decode data",
      "to convert from serial to parallel data"
    ],
    "correct": "to convert from one number system to other",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "In the binary number “10011” the weight of the most significant digit is ____",
    "options": [
      "$2^4$ (2 raise to power 4)",
      "$2^3$ (2 raise to power 3)",
      "$2^0$ (2 raise to power 0)",
      "$2^1$ (2 raise to power 1)"
    ],
    "correct": "$2^4$ (2 raise to power 4)",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "An S-R latch can be implemented by using _________ gates",
    "options": [
      "AND, OR",
      "NAND, NOR",
      "NAND, XOR",
      "NOT, XOR"
    ],
    "correct": "NAND, NOR",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "A latch has _____ stable states",
    "options": [
      "One",
      "Two",
      "Three",
      "Four"
    ],
    "correct": "Two",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Sequential circuits have storage elements",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "The ABEL symbol for “XOR” operation is",
    "options": [
      "$",
      "#",
      "!",
      "&"
    ],
    "correct": "$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "A Demultiplexer is not available commercially.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Using multiplexer as parallel to serial converter requires ___________ connected to the multiplexer",
    "options": [
      "A parallel to serial converter circuit",
      "A counter circuit",
      "A BCD to Decimal decoder",
      "A 2-to-8 bit decoder"
    ],
    "correct": "A counter circuit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The device shown here is most likely a ",
    "options": [
      "Comparator",
      "Multiplexer",
      "Demultiplexer",
      "Parity generator"
    ],
    "correct": "Multiplexer",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "The main use of the Multiplexer is to",
    "options": [
      "Select data from multiple sources and to route it to a single Destination",
      "Select data from Single source and to route it to a multiple Destinations",
      "Select data from Single source and to route to single destination",
      "Select data from multiple sources and to route to multiple destinations"
    ],
    "correct": "Select data from multiple sources and to route it to a single Destination",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "A logic circuit with an output $X=\\overline{A}BC+A\\overline{B}$ consists of ________.",
    "options": [
      "two AND gates, two OR gates, two inverters",
      "three AND gates, two OR gates, one inverter",
      "two AND gates, one OR gate, two inverters",
      "two AND gates, one OR gate"
    ],
    "correct": "two AND gates, one OR gate, two inverters",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "The binary value of 1010 is converted to the product term $\\overline{A} B \\overline{C} D$.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "The 3-variable Karnaugh Map (K-Map) has _______ cells for min or max terms",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "8",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Following is standard POS expression $(\\overline{A}+B+\\overline{C}+D)(A+\\overline{B}+C+\\overline{D})(A+B+\\overline{C}+\\overline{D})(A+B+C+\\overline{D})(A+\\overline{B}+\\overline{C}+D)$",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "The output of the expression $F=A+B+C$ will be Logic ________ when $A=0$, $B=1$, $C=1$. the symbol'+' here represents OR Gate.",
    "options": [
      "Undefined",
      "One",
      "Zero",
      "10 (binary)"
    ],
    "correct": "One",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "The Extended ASCII Code (American Standard Code for Information Interchange) is a _____ code",
    "options": [
      "2-bit",
      "7-bit",
      "8-bit",
      "16-bit"
    ],
    "correct": "8-bit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "The diagram given below represents ",
    "options": [
      "Demorgans law",
      "Associative law",
      "Product of sum form",
      "Sum of product form"
    ],
    "correct": "Product of sum form",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "According to Demorgan’s theorem: $\\overline{A+B+C}$ = _________",
    "options": [
      "A.B.C",
      "$A+\\overline{B.C}$",
      "$\\overline{A}.\\overline{B}.\\overline{C}$",
      "$\\overline{AB}+C$"
    ],
    "correct": "$\\overline{A}.\\overline{B}.\\overline{C}$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "The Extended ASCII Code (American Standard Code for Information Interchange) is a _____ code",
    "options": [
      "2-bit",
      "7-bit",
      "8-bit",
      "16-bit"
    ],
    "correct": "8-bit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "The AND Gate performs a logical __________function",
    "options": [
      "Addition",
      "Subtraction",
      "Multiplication",
      "Division"
    ],
    "correct": "Multiplication",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "NOR gate is formed by connecting _________",
    "options": [
      "OR Gate and then NOT Gate",
      "NOT Gate and then OR Gate",
      "AND Gate and then OR Gate",
      "OR Gate and then AND Gate"
    ],
    "correct": "OR Gate and then NOT Gate",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Generally, the Power dissipation of _______ devices remains constant throughout their operation.",
    "options": [
      "TTL",
      "CMOS 3.5 series",
      "CMOS 5 Series",
      "Power dissipation of all circuits increases with time."
    ],
    "correct": "TTL",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Two 2-bit comparator circuits can be connected to form single 4-bit comparator",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "When the control line in tri-state buffer is high the buffer operates like a ________ gate",
    "options": [
      "AND",
      "OR",
      "NOT",
      "XOR"
    ],
    "correct": "NOT",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "The GAL22V10 has ____ inputs",
    "options": [
      "22",
      "10",
      "44",
      "20"
    ],
    "correct": "22",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "The ABEL symbol for “OR” operation is",
    "options": [
      "!",
      "&",
      "#",
      "$"
    ],
    "correct": "#",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "The OLMC of the GAL16V8 is _______ to the OLMC of the GAL22V10",
    "options": [
      "Similar",
      "Different",
      "Similar with some enhancements",
      "Depends on the type of PALs input size"
    ],
    "correct": "Different",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "All the ABEL equations must end with ________",
    "options": [
      "“ . “ (a dot)",
      "“ $ “ (a dollar symbol)",
      "“ ; “ (a semicolon)",
      "“ endl “ (keyword “endl”)"
    ],
    "correct": "“ ; “ (a semicolon)",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "The Quad Multiplexer has _____ outputs",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "4",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "\"Sum-of-Weights\" method is used __________",
    "options": [
      "to convert from one number system to other",
      "to encode data",
      "to decode data",
      "to convert from serial to parralel data"
    ],
    "correct": "to convert from one number system to other",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Circuits having a bubble at their outputs are considered to have an active-low output.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "$(A+B)(A+B+C)(A+C)$ is an example of ______________",
    "options": [
      "Product of sum form",
      "Sum of product form",
      "Demorgans law",
      "Associative law"
    ],
    "correct": "Product of sum form",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Which one is true:",
    "options": [
      "Power consumption of TTL is higher than of CMOS",
      "Power consumption of CMOS is higher than of TTL",
      "Both TTL and CMOS have same power consumption",
      "Power consumption of both CMOS and TTL depends on no. of gates in the circuit."
    ],
    "correct": "Power consumption of TTL is higher than of CMOS",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "The maximum number that can be represented using unsigned octal system is _______",
    "options": [
      "1",
      "7",
      "9",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "7",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "If we add “723” and “134” by representing them in floating point notation i.e. by first, converting them in floating point representation and then adding them, the value of exponent of result will be ________",
    "options": [
      "0",
      "1",
      "2",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct": "3",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "The diagram given below represents ",
    "options": [
      "Demorgans law",
      "Associative law",
      "Product of sum form",
      "Sum of product form"
    ],
    "correct": "Product of sum form",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "The range of Excess-8 code is from ______ to ______",
    "options": [
      "+7 to -8",
      "+8 to -7",
      "+9 to -8",
      "-9 to +8"
    ],
    "correct": "+7 to -8",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "A non-standard POS is converted into a standard POS by using the rule _____ ",
    "options": [
      "$A+\\overline{A}=1$",
      "$A\\overline{A}=0$",
      "$1+A=1$",
      "$A+B=B+A$"
    ],
    "correct": "$A+\\overline{A}=1$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "The 3-variable Karnaugh Map (K-Map) has _______ cells for min or max terms",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "8",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "The binary numbers A = 1100 and B = 1001 are applied to the inputs of a comparator. What are the output levels?",
    "options": [
      "$A > B = 1, A < B = 0, A < B = 1$",
      "$A > B = 0, A < B = 1, A = B = 0$",
      "$A > B = 1, A < B = 0, A = B = 0$",
      "$A > B = 0, A < B = 1, A = B = 1$"
    ],
    "correct": "$A > B = 1, A < B = 0, A = B = 0$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "A particular Full Adder has",
    "options": [
      "3 inputs and 2 output",
      "3 inputs and 3 output",
      "2 inputs and 3 output",
      "2 inputs and 2 output"
    ],
    "correct": "3 inputs and 2 output",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "The function to be performed by the processor is selected by set of inputs known as _ _ _ _ _ _ _ _",
    "options": [
      "Function Select Inputs",
      "MicroOperation selectors",
      "OPCODE Selectors",
      "None of given option"
    ],
    "correct": "Function Select Inputs",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "For a 3-to-8 decoder how many 2-to-4 decoders will be required?",
    "options": [
      "2",
      "1",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct": "2",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "GAL is an acronym for ________.",
    "options": [
      "Giant Array Logic",
      "General Array Logic",
      "Generic Array Logic",
      "Generic Analysis Logic"
    ],
    "correct": "Generic Array Logic",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "The Quad Multiplexer has _____ outputs",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "4",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "$A.(B.C) = (A.B).C$ is an expression of __________",
    "options": [
      "Demorgan’s Law",
      "Distributive Law",
      "Commutative Law",
      "Associative Law"
    ],
    "correct": "Associative Law",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "2's complement of any binary number can be calculated by",
    "options": [
      "adding 1's complement twice",
      "adding 1 to 1's complement",
      "subtracting 1 from 1's complement.",
      "calculating 1's complement and inverting most significant bit"
    ],
    "correct": "adding 1 to 1's complement",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "The binary value “1010110” is equivalent to decimal __________",
    "options": [
      "86",
      "87",
      "88",
      "89"
    ],
    "correct": "86",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "Tri-State Buffer is basically a/an _________ gate.",
    "options": [
      "AND",
      "OR",
      "NOT",
      "XOR"
    ],
    "correct": "NOT",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "GAL can be reprogrammed because instead of fuses _______ logic is used in it",
    "options": [
      "$E^2$ CMOS",
      "TTL",
      "CMOS+",
      "None of the given options"
    ],
    "correct": "$E^2$ CMOS",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "The device shown here is most likely a ",
    "options": [
      "Comparator",
      "Multiplexer",
      "Demultiplexer",
      "Parity generator"
    ],
    "correct": "Multiplexer",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "If “1110” is applied at the input of BCD-to-Decimal decoder which output pin will be activated?",
    "options": [
      "$2^{nd}$",
      "$4^{th}$",
      "$14^{th}$",
      "No output wire will be activated"
    ],
    "correct": "No output wire will be activated",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "Half-Adder Logic circuit contains 2 XOR Gates",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "A particular Full Adder has",
    "options": [
      "3 inputs and 2 output",
      "3 inputs and 3 output",
      "2 inputs and 3 output",
      "2 inputs and 2 output"
    ],
    "correct": "3 inputs and 2 output",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "Sum $= A \\oplus B \\oplus C$, $\\text{CarryOut} = C(A \\oplus B)+AB$ are the Sum and CarryOut expression of",
    "options": [
      "Half Adder",
      "Full Adder",
      "3-bit parralel adder",
      "MSI adder cicuit"
    ],
    "correct": "Full Adder",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "A Karnaugh map is similar to a truth table because it presents all the possible values of input variables and the resulting output of each value.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "The output $A < B$ is set to 1 when the input combinations is __________",
    "options": [
      "$A=10$, $B=01$",
      "$A=11$, $B=01$",
      "$A=01$, $B=01$",
      "$A=01$, $B=10$"
    ],
    "correct": "$A=01$, $B=10$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "The 4-variable Karnaugh Map (K-Map) has _______ cells for min or max terms",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "16",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "Generally, the Power dissipation of _______ devices remains constant throughout their operation.",
    "options": [
      "TTL",
      "CMOS 3.5 series",
      "CMOS 5 Series",
      "Power dissipation of all circuits increases with time."
    ],
    "correct": "TTL",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "The decimal “8” is represented as _________ using Gray-Code.",
    "options": [
      "0011",
      "1100",
      "1000",
      "1010"
    ],
    "correct": "1100",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "$(A+B).(A+C)$ = ___________",
    "options": [
      "$B+C$",
      "$A+BC$",
      "$AB+C$",
      "$AC+B$"
    ],
    "correct": "$A+BC$",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "$A.(B + C) = A.B + A.C$ is the expression of _________________",
    "options": [
      "Demorgan’s Law",
      "Commutative Law",
      "Distributive Law",
      "Associative Law"
    ],
    "correct": "Distributive Law",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "NOR Gate can be used to perform the operation of AND, OR and NOT Gate",
    "options": [
      "FALSE",
      "TRUE"
    ],
    "correct": "TRUE",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "In ANSI/IEEE Standard 754 “Mantissa” is represented by ___ - bits______ bits",
    "options": [
      "8-bits",
      "16-bits",
      "32-bits",
      "64-bits"
    ],
    "correct": "64-bits",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "Caveman number system is Base ______ number system",
    "options": [
      "2",
      "5",
      "10",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "5",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "Which of the number is not a representative of hexadecimal system",
    "options": [
      "1234",
      "ABCD",
      "1001",
      "DEFH"
    ],
    "correct": "DEFH",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "The Unsigned Binary representation can only represent positive binary numbers",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "The values that exceed the specified range can not be correctly represented and are considered as ________",
    "options": [
      "Overflow",
      "Carry",
      "Parity",
      "Sign value"
    ],
    "correct": "Overflow",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "The 4-bit 2’s complement representation of “-7” is _____________",
    "options": [
      "0111",
      "1111",
      "1001",
      "0110"
    ],
    "correct": "1001",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "$\\overline{A}B+\\overline{A}B\\overline{C}+AC$ is an example of ________",
    "options": [
      "Product of sum form",
      "Sum of product form",
      "Demorgans law",
      "Associative law"
    ],
    "correct": "Sum of product form",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "The diagram given below represents ",
    "options": [
      "Demorgans law",
      "Associative law",
      "Product of sum form",
      "Sum of product form"
    ],
    "correct": "Sum of product form",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "The output of an AND gate is one when _______",
    "options": [
      "All of the inputs are one",
      "Any of the input is one",
      "Any of the input is zero",
      "All the inputs are zero"
    ],
    "correct": "All of the inputs are one",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "The 4-variable Karnaugh Map (K-Map) has _______ cells for min or max terms",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "12",
      "16"
    ],
    "correct": "16",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "A BCD to 7-Segment decoder has",
    "options": [
      "3 inputs and 7 outputs",
      "4 inputs and 7 outputs",
      "7 inputs and 3 outputs",
      "7 inputs and 4 outputs"
    ],
    "correct": "4 inputs and 7 outputs",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "Two 2-input, 4-bit multiplexers 74X157 can be connected to implement a ____ multiplexer.",
    "options": [
      "4-input, 8-bit",
      "4-input, 16-bit",
      "2-input, 8-bit",
      "2-input, 4-bit"
    ],
    "correct": "2-input, 8-bit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "The PROM consists of a fixed non-programmable ____________ Gate array configured as a decoder.",
    "options": [
      "AND",
      "OR",
      "NOT",
      "XOR"
    ],
    "correct": "AND",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "In ABEL the variable ‘A’ is treated separately from variable ‘a’",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "The ABEL notation equivalent to Boolean expression $A+B$ is:",
    "options": [
      "A & B",
      "A ! B",
      "A # B",
      "A $ B"
    ],
    "correct": "A # B",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "If an active-HIGH S-R latch has a 0 on the S input and a 1 on the R input and then the R input goes to 0, the latch will be ________.",
    "options": [
      "SET",
      "RESET",
      "Clear",
      "Invalid"
    ],
    "correct": "RESET",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "Demultiplexer has",
    "options": [
      "Single input and single outputs.",
      "Multiple inputs and multiple outputs.",
      "Single input and multiple outputs.",
      "Multiple inputs and single output."
    ],
    "correct": "Single input and multiple outputs.",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Which one is true:",
    "options": [
      "Power consumption of TTL is higher than of CMOS",
      "Power consumption of CMOS is higher than of TTL",
      "Both TTL and CMOS have same power consumption",
      "Power consumption of both CMOS and TTL depends on no. of gates in the circuit."
    ],
    "correct": "Power consumption of TTL is higher than of CMOS",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  }
]